<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Laird Streak`s Blog</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://LairdStreak.github.io/</id><updated>2024-12-04T12:46:00+13:00</updated><entry><title>Journal Entry</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/journal-entry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-04T12:46:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T12:46:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2024-12-04:/journal-entry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a heartbroken person.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The quote, "For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also" (Matthew 6:21), speaks to the idea that what we value and prioritize in life will reveal where our deepest affections lie. In the context of love, this passage can be understood as a reminder that the people, relationships, or things we cherish the most are the ones we invest our hearts and time in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When it comes to whom we love, this verse suggests that love is not merely an emotion or feeling but an active choice. Our love follows where we place our attention and devotion. For instance, if we treasure relationships with family, friends, or a significant other, our hearts will naturally turn toward them. Likewise, if we prioritize our career, wealth, or personal achievements, those things will take center stage in our hearts.

To love someone deeply means making them a priority in your life. It is through investing time, energy, and care into someone that love is nurtured and deepened. The more we cherish and value a person, the more our hearts are inclined toward them.

On a spiritual level, this verse can also point to the idea that when we center our lives around God and His love, our hearts are transformed. The way we love others is deeply connected to the way we view and treasure God's love for us. As we treasure His love, we begin to reflect that love in the way we care for those closest to us.

In summary, "where your treasure is, there your heart will be also" calls us to consider what we value in love and relationships. It challenges us to ensure that our love is not just a fleeting emotion but a reflection of where we truly place our heart.

&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="Journal"></category></entry><entry><title>An Attitude of Gratitude</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/an-attitude-of-gratitude.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-02T19:57:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T19:57:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2024-12-02:/an-attitude-of-gratitude.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Attitude of Gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is an attitude of gratitude you may be asking?
Even when all else fails and you are in the depths of dispair remember there is allways hope.
&lt;br/&gt;
I am in a terrible place at this time due to lack of focus and being un-able to stick to promises made and best efforts I have let someone down.
&lt;br/&gt;
But even in the worst times there is a rescue God loves me with my flaws and all.
This song is a reminder and I hope it can help some-one else also struggling.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/0PT7AYi17BlmeOdfQAwgGX?si=c822154c8a1a40b2"&gt;Beloved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="Journal"></category></entry><entry><title>2024-12-02 Journal Entry</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/2024-12-02-journal-entry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-02T12:23:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T12:23:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2024-12-02:/2024-12-02-journal-entry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Journal entry.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Time... it's the great equalizer. As time goes by, we slowly forget the things that once mattered most. We become consumed by the constant demands of our daily lives—work, routines, obligations—and before we know it, we’ve become distracted by the meaningless noise around us. The busy moments cloud our vision, and we lose sight of what once made us feel whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relationships, the very foundation of our joy and fulfillment, begin to slip through the cracks. We stop prioritizing the people who matter, as we convince ourselves that there will always be time for love later, or that we can fix things 'when things calm down.' But time doesn’t wait for anyone. It keeps moving, and with each passing day, the connection we had with others starts to fade, like an image losing focus. We forget to nurture our bonds, and in doing so, we fall out of love—not just with others, but sometimes with ourselves, as we neglect the things that truly matter. We allow life’s distractions to drown out the quiet moments that once brought us closer to the ones we cherish most. And before we know it, we find ourselves yearning for what we lost, wishing we had remembered to appreciate it before it was too late."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reflection emphasizes how time, along with the distractions and demands of life, can cause us to forget the value of relationships, leading to a slow drift from the ones we love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="Journal"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacktober Fest 2023 Update</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/hacktober-fest-2023-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-12T20:44:00+13:00</published><updated>2023-10-12T20:44:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-10-12:/hacktober-fest-2023-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hacktober Fest 2023 participant.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I have completed the following for Hacktober 2023.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/participant.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/participant2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/level2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/tree.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><category term="Development"></category><category term="Development"></category></entry><entry><title>Gratefulness Journal Entry 2</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/gratefulness-journal-entry-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-12T11:38:00+13:00</published><updated>2023-10-12T11:38:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-10-12:/gratefulness-journal-entry-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I grateful for today?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;My wonderful family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is something positive that happened today?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Had a wonderful night of peaceful sleep&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Getting my car back from the mechanics&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Fluff"></category><category term="Fluff"></category></entry><entry><title>Embracing the Excitement: Why I Want to Participate in Hacktoberfest 2023</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/embracing-the-excitement-why-i-want-to-participate-in-hacktoberfest-2023.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-02T16:49:00+13:00</published><updated>2023-10-02T16:49:00+13:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-10-02:/embracing-the-excitement-why-i-want-to-participate-in-hacktoberfest-2023.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hacktober Fest 2023 participant.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;WHY?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;HacktoberFest 2023&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/logo.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, the world of open source software has always fascinated me. The collaborative nature of building and improving software, sharing knowledge, and giving back to the community resonates deeply with my passion for coding. Hacktoberfest, an annual event organized by DigitalOcean and GitHub, offers an incredible opportunity to channel this passion and contribute meaningfully to open source projects. In this essay, I will explain why I am eagerly looking forward to participating in Hacktoberfest 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community and Collaboration:&lt;/strong&gt; Hacktoberfest is a celebration of the global open source community. It brings together developers from all corners of the world, fostering a sense of camaraderie and collaboration that is unparalleled. Engaging with fellow developers, exchanging ideas, and working together on open source projects is a valuable experience. It allows me to grow not only as a developer but also as a member of a vibrant and diverse community.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill Enhancement:&lt;/strong&gt; Contributing to open source projects challenges me to expand my skill set. It pushes me to explore new technologies, programming languages, and frameworks. Whether it's fixing a bug, adding a new feature, or optimizing code, these contributions provide opportunities to learn and improve. Hacktoberfest is a platform where I can take on various challenges and broaden my horizons.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving Back:&lt;/strong&gt; The open source community has given me access to an abundance of free, high-quality software. Contributing to open source projects during Hacktoberfest is a way for me to give back to this community that has nurtured my growth as a developer. It's a chance to contribute to projects that have been instrumental in my own work and help others benefit from my contributions.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Networking:&lt;/strong&gt; Hacktoberfest is not just about code; it's also about building connections. Participating in this event allows me to connect with developers, maintainers, and organizations that share my interests. These connections can lead to future collaborations, job opportunities, and a broader professional network.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resume and Portfolio:&lt;/strong&gt; Open source contributions are a valuable addition to my developer portfolio. They demonstrate my skills, commitment to coding, and ability to work in a team. Having a track record of Hacktoberfest contributions showcases my dedication to the open source ethos and can be an attractive point for potential employers.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem Solving:&lt;/strong&gt; Open source projects often present complex problems and challenges that require creative solutions. By participating in Hacktoberfest, I can sharpen my problem-solving skills. It's an opportunity to tackle real-world issues and find innovative ways to address them, which is an essential skill in the tech industry.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognition and Rewards:&lt;/strong&gt; The feeling of accomplishment that comes with successfully completing Hacktoberfest challenges is incredibly rewarding. Earning a limited-edition Hacktoberfest  digital badges adds a sense of achievement to the experience.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond technical skills, Hacktoberfest fosters personal growth. It teaches discipline, time management, and perseverance. Meeting the challenge of contributing to open source projects within the given time frame requires dedication and determination, qualities that are beneficial in all aspects of life.
&lt;br /&gt;
In conclusion, my eagerness to participate in Hacktoberfest 2023 stems from a deep-rooted passion for coding, community, and collaboration. This event offers a unique platform for developers like me to give back to the open source community, enhance our skills, and connect with like-minded individuals. It is an opportunity for personal and professional growth that I eagerly anticipate and look forward to. Hacktoberfest is not just a coding event; it's a celebration of the spirit of open source, and I am excited to be a part of it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off Laird Streak (aka code grunt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Development"></category><category term="Development"></category></entry><entry><title>20 Steps to Elevate Your Career from Intermediate to Senior Developer</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/20-steps-to-elevate-your-career-from-intermediate-to-senior-developer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-22T22:19:00+12:00</published><updated>2023-09-22T22:19:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-09-22:/20-steps-to-elevate-your-career-from-intermediate-to-senior-developer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Soft Skills.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Becoming a senior developer is a rewarding journey that demands a combination of technical expertise, soft skills, and a commitment to growth.
Here are 20 essential tips to help you make this leap in your career**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master Your Tech Stack&lt;/strong&gt; Deepen your knowledge of the programming languages and frameworks you work with regularly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Code Quality Matters&lt;/strong&gt; Write clean, maintainable code. Focus on adhering to best practices and coding standards consistently.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Seek Feedback Actively&lt;/strong&gt; Embrace feedback from code reviews and colleagues. Use it as a tool for growth.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Learn from Seniors&lt;/strong&gt; Collaborate with senior developers. Observe their practices, ask questions, and learn from their experience.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Own Your Work&lt;/strong&gt; Take ownership of your projects. Be accountable for their success and actively resolve issues that arise.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dive into Design Patterns&lt;/strong&gt; Familiarize yourself with common design patterns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Contribute to Open Source&lt;/strong&gt; Participate in open-source projects to gain exposure to advanced coding practices and collaboration with experienced developers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mentorship&lt;/strong&gt; Share your knowledge with junior developers. Teaching others can deepen your own understanding.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Documentation Matters&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain clear and up-to-date project documentation. It demonstrates professionalism and helps your team.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Stay Updated&lt;/strong&gt; Keep abreast of industry trends, new tools, and emerging technologies. Continuous learning is key.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Practice Effective Communication&lt;/strong&gt; Enhance your communication skills, both written and verbal. Being able to convey ideas clearly is invaluable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Embrace Leadership&lt;/strong&gt; Take on leadership roles in projects when opportunities arise.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Networking&lt;/strong&gt; Attend tech conferences, meetups, and online forums to build a professional network.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Adopt Agile Practices&lt;/strong&gt; Familiarize yourself with Agile methodologies like Scrum.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Explore New Horizons&lt;/strong&gt; Be open to new technologies and methodologies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mastery of Tools&lt;/strong&gt; Become proficient in development tools and IDEs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Patience and Perseverance&lt;/strong&gt; Remember that the journey to becoming a senior developer is a marathon, not a sprint. Stay patient and committed to continuous improvement.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Evolving from an intermediate developer to a senior developer is a process. Embrace each step, stay curious, and keep pushing your boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Soft Skills"></category><category term="Soft Skills"></category></entry><entry><title>My Mini Review</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/my-mini-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-18T13:03:00+12:00</published><updated>2023-09-18T13:03:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-09-18:/my-mini-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Personal Resin review.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;My brief review of Anycubic's water washable resin versus Esun's water washable resin.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this brief comparison, I'll be sharing my thoughts on Anycubic's water washable resin versus Esun's water washable resin in white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that Esun's water washable resin offers good value for its price, but it comes with a few drawbacks. One notable issue is that the prints tend to fade when exposed to sunlight during the curing process. Additionally, over time, these prints can develop unsightly cracks, which was rather disappointing. On a positive note, this resin proved easier to remove from supports and rafts compared to Anycubic's resin. However, I was somewhat let down by the color, as it leaned more towards a milky, creamy white rather than a crisp, bright white that would complement 3D printed models effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I'm currently quite impressed with Anycubic's water washable resin. I have several models still in the process of printing on my 3D printer, and the quality is consistently high. The white hue is strikingly bright and appears to cure more effectively than Esun's counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, this concludes my initial assessment. I plan to follow up with another post, complete with images showcasing the differences between the prints, and I'll offer my final verdict based on my personal preference and how well each resin performs for my specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links:
&lt;a href="https://www.anycubic.com/collections/water-wash-resin"&gt;anycubic&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.esun3d.com/water-washable-resin-product/"&gt;esun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobby"></category><category term="Hobby"></category><category term="anycubic"></category><category term="esun"></category><category term="Creality Halot One"></category></entry><entry><title>Gratefulness Journal Entry 1</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/gratefulness-journal-entry-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T20:55:00+12:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T20:55:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-09-17:/gratefulness-journal-entry-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remind yourself how lucky you are.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Just decide that, “I’m going to give it everything I’ve got, to make this day a beautiful day.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I’m going to be kind to everyone I meet. I’m going to be gentle and sweet to everyone, even if they hate me. I love my life and I look forward to today.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Some Gratitude Quotes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As we express our gratitude, we must never forget that the highest appreciation is not to utter words but to live by them.” —John F. Kennedy
“I awoke this morning with devout thanksgiving for my friends, the old and the new.” —Ralph Waldo Emerson
 “Reflect upon your present blessings—of which every man has many—not on your past misfortunes, of which all men have some.” —Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a great time and remember to always be grateful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Fluff"></category><category term="Fluff"></category></entry><entry><title>My ADHD Journey Post</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/my-adhd-journey-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-17T18:45:00+12:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T18:45:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2023-09-17:/my-adhd-journey-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mental Health.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery.&lt;/strong&gt;
For a while I suspected I may have ADHD(&lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attention_deficit_hyperactivity_disorder_predominantly_inattentive' _target='_blank'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) due to being consistently unfocused and unable to work on one task at a time.
Constantly struggling to pay attention to details, being easily distracted, and often have trouble organizing or finishing tasks.
Finally got an ADHD Diagnosis and things are going a lot better.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I highly recommend these two books.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.paperplus.co.nz/shop/books/this-is-adhd"&gt;This is ADHD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.paperplus.co.nz/shop/books/non-fiction/health-wellbeing/medicine/i-am-autistic"&gt;I am autistic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some good resources to read up on.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href="https://mentalhealth.org.nz/conditions/condition/adhd-in-adults?gclid=CjwKCAjwgZCoBhBnEiwAz35RwnWpYfoHc-wa5ThltB53VDA5fKKp8f5QCtJ36TJ0WQN5eUb2Ij5f3BoC__MQAvD_BwE"&gt;mentalhealth.org.nz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mental Health"></category><category term="Mental Health"></category></entry><entry><title>My New Hobby</title><link href="https://LairdStreak.github.io/my-new-hobby.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-02T13:03:00+12:00</published><updated>2022-05-02T13:03:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Laird Streak</name></author><id>tag:lairdstreak.github.io,2022-05-02:/my-new-hobby.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My New Hobby.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I have just recently gotten into a new hobby.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D Printing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;These are the two machines I currently own.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1: Creality Ender 3v2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/ender-3-V2-01.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few prints:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/20220401_144142.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/20220318_091638.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/20211121_124218.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/20211009_200114.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2: Creality Halot One&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/Halot-One.jpg" /&gt;
Here is a sample print:
&lt;img src="https://LairdStreak.github.io/images/20220414_084649.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobby"></category><category term="Hobby, Creality, Halot One"></category><category term="Ender 3"></category></entry></feed>